Guide to the Cipe Pineles papers, 1925-2005 and undated RL.11739
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Organizations, 1947-1989 and undated; 4
  - Parsons School of Design, 1963-1988 and undated; 14
    - Cheap Eats: The Art Student's Coloring Cook Book, 1975; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Cheap Eats proof pages, 1975 (Box 19)
    - Cipe Pineles critique: I've Had It with Cipe Pineles, undated (Box 4)
    - Cipe Pineles Scholarship in Design--Program, contributions, luncheon, etc., 1983; 11 folders (Box 4)
    - Commencement, 1971-1974; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Design materials, event invitation samples, etc., 1972-1978 (Box 4)
    - Division of Continuing Education, 1980; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Division of Continuing Education, 1981; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Event invitation and programs, 1964-1984; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Exhibition announcements, 1976-1980 (Box 5)
    - Faculty address list, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
    - Fashion in Paris, 1988 (Box 5)
    - First Annual Environmental Design Award dinner, 1984 (Box 5)
    - General booklet, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - Graduating class portraits, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Honorary Doctorate, 1986 (Box 18)
    - I'm Virginia Ham, Fry Me--Parsons cookbook, undated (Box 5)
    - Informational pamphlet, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Instructions for completing application for admission, undated (Box 5)
    - Lake Placid summer workshops, 1982 (Box 10)
    - Logo design, undated (Box 5)
    - Master of Arts program in history of decorative arts, undated (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous design work, undated (Box 19)
    - New School campus, undated (Box 5)
    - New York, Los Angeles, Paris poster, undated (Box 5)
    - News release, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter, 1973-1978 (Box 5)
    - Newsletter, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Otis Art Institute, 1978-1979; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Parsons Greenwich Village, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Parsons in Paris, 1979-1981; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Parsons in Paris, Italy and Great Britain, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Parsons in West Africa, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Parsons New School apprenticeship programs, undated (Box 5)
    - Parsons New York/Otis Los Angeles, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    - Parsons pamphlet fruit designs, undated (Box 5)
    - Parsons Professionals, undated (Box 5)
    - Photography in Paris, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Posters, undated (Oversize-folder 2)
    - Posters, undated (Oversize-folder 3)
    - Posters, undated (Oversize-folder 4)
    - Posters, 1972-1979; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Promotional materials, undated (Box 18)
    - Robert Steven Levin Bachelor of Fine Arts, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Stationery designs, undated; 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Student Handbook and Guide to Greenwich Village, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    - Summer evening classes, 1975 (Box 5)
    - The Big Apple/The Big Orange, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
    - The Big Apple Sunrise, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - Walter Rosenblum's People of the South Bronx, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Pratt Institute, 1965-1985; 15
    - Alumnus, 1965-1967; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Commencement, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - Rockland Country Day School, 1963-1970 and undated; 16
    - Benefit performance--You're a Good Man, Charlie Brown, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Brochure, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1970; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Design materials, undated (Box 5)
    - Developmental reading program, 1963 (Box 5)
    - "Dylan" event invitation, undated (Box 5)
    - Graduation certificate design, undated (Box 5)
    - On a Clear Day You Can See Forever event invitation, 1965 (Box 5)
    - Reply cards, undated (Box 5)
    - Summer session, 1964 (Box 5)
    - The Innocent Fox, 1964 (Box 5)
- People, 1930-2005 and undated; 5
  - Bertha Pineles, 1937-1949; 17
    - Certificate of death, 1949 (Box 5)
    - Condolences, 1949 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1949; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Carol Burtin, 1962-1974 and undated; 18
    - A Beach Scene, undated (Box 5)
    - Burtin-Fripp adoption correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - Burtin-Fripp adoption correspondence, 1973 (Box 10)
    - Clouds, undated (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Germany after the War, undated (Box 5)
    - Joe Hyde wedding guest list, 1965 (Box 5)
    - "Miss Burtin Is Engaged to Mr. Fripp" (article), approximately 1965 (Box 5)
    - Wedding invitation, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Debora Pineles, 1930-1976; 19
    - Clippings, 1939 (Box 18)
    - Clippings, 1939-1976 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1960; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - School of Nursing of the Jewish Hospital commencement, 1930 (Box 5)
  - Denis Nowell Pritt, 1972; 20
    - Memorial service, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Edgar Levy, 1975; 21
    - Condolences, 1975; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Jack Pineles, 1963-1965; 22
    - Financial, 1963-1965 (Box 5)
  - Janet Benson Chatfield-Taylor, 1960; 23
    - Wedding invitation (Simeon Braguin), 1960 (Box 5)
  - Joel Levy, 1965; 24
    - Employment application letter, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Mehemed Fehmy Agha, 1939; 25
    - PM Magazine, Agha's American Decade (tribute feature), 1939 (Box 6)
  - Tom Golden, 1951-2005 and undated; 26
    - Barn restoration project, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1977; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 10)
    - Correspondence--Adoption congratulations, 1951; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence--Art schools, 1967-1968 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence--Keith de Lellis, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence--Rochester Institute of Technology, 2005 (Box 6)
      With Kari Horowicz, Art and Photography Librarian, regarding A Symposium on Magazines for Women and the Legacy of Cipe Pineles
    - Drawings, 1957-1971; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Expired passport, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Name picking notes, undated (Box 6)
    - Postcards to Tom, 1959-1963 (Box 6)
    - Rockland artists master list, 2005 (Box 6)
    - Tom and Cipe at Rockland Country Day School (clippings), 1960 (Box 6)
  - Will Burtin, 1960-1974 and undated; 27
    - Anniversary congratulations, undated (Box 6)
    - Biography, undated (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1974 and undated; 8 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 10)
    - Estate materials, undated (Box 10)
    - Obituary (Art Directors Club newsletter AD Cryer first issue), 1972 (Box 18)
    - Wedding materials, 1960-1961; 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Who's Who in the East, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Will Fripp, 1969-1977; 28
    - Birth announcement, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Drawing, 1977 (Box 6)
  - William Golden, 1938-1960 and undated; 29
    - Art Director of the Year, 1960 (Box 6)
    - Bon voyages messages, 1949 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence with Cipe Pineles, 1938-1958; 9 folders (Box 6)
      Includes World War II era and Golden's military service
    - Correspondence--Condolences, 1959; 8 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence--Condolences, 1959-1960; 9 folders (Box 7)
    - Directors and officers of CBS divisions, 1957 (Box 7)
    - Donations to heart associations in memory of William Golden, 1959 (Box 7)
    - How CBS-TV's "Eye" Symbol Nearly Died, undated (Box 7)
    - Marriage certificate, 1942 (Box 7)
    - Memo pads, undated (Box 7)
    - Name change, 1949 (Box 7)
      William and Cipe Goldberg to Golden
    - Name change, 1949 (Box 10)
    - New house congratulations, 1955 (Box 7)
    - "Our Home Run" SS Argentina, 1945 (Box 7)
    - Queen of Bermuda passenger list, 1939 (Box 7)
    - Tribute, 1960 (Box 7)
- Photographs, 1925-1989 and undated; 6
  - Art Directors Club, undated (Box 8)
  - Aspen judging, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Beach vacation, undated (Box 8)
  - Bertha Pineles, undated (Box 8)
  - Bertha Pineles, 1940s (Box 14)
  - Book pages, magazine layouts, 1939-1984 (Box 8)
  - Children, 1988-1989 and undated (Box 8)
  - Children, 1949-1971 and undated (Box 14)
  - Cipe and Will Burtin, undated (Box 8)
  - Cipe and William Golden, undated (Box 8)
  - Cipe Pineles, undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Cipe Pineles, 1980s (Box 10)
  - Cipe Pineles by Norman Parkinson, approximately 1937 (Box 18)
  - Commemoration of Will Burtin memorial exhibition at American Embassy in London, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Events, undated (Box 8)
  - Events, 1960-1980s and undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Family and friends, 1920s-1980s; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Family and friends, 1920s-1980s; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Family and friends, 1928-1986 and undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Film strips, undated (Box 14)
  - Fruit, 1985 and undated (Box 9)
  - Funeral, undated (Box 9)
  - Holiday cards, 1962 and undated (Box 9)
  - Home, interior, undated (Box 9)
  - Lincoln Center, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Miniatures, undated (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1920s-1980s (Box 18)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Will Burtin address the students at Art Center School, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Nature, undated (Box 9)
  - Outdoor, undated (Box 14)
  - Parsons, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Pencils, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Portraits, 1930-1970 and undated (Box 9)
  - Pratt, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Recipe books, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Siobhan McKenna "small worlds", 1959 (Box 9)
  - Speaking Out, undated (Box 9)
  - Thomas Golden, 1952-1954 and undated; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Thomas Golden, Will Fripp, 1952-1971 and undated (Box 14)
  - Typography examples, undated (Box 9)
  - U.S. military luncheon, 1940s (Box 9)
  - Vivian Beaumont Theater, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Will Burtin, undated (Box 9)
  - Will Burtin, undated (Box 18)